<resources xmlns:tools="http://schemas.android.com/tools">
    <string name="app_name" translatable="false">Hike Palace</string>
    <string name="txt_home">Home</string>
    <string name="txt_search">Search</string>
    <string name="txt_places_list">Places List</string>
    <string name="txt_account">Account</string>
    <string name="txt_more"><![CDATA[More >>]]></string>
    <string name="txt_place_description">Place Description</string>
    <string name="txt_mountains_list">Mountains List</string>
    <string name="txt_name">Mount %s</string>
    <string name="txt_suggested">Suggested by %s people</string>
    <string name="txt_words_from_hikers">Words from Hikers</string>
    <string name="txt_discover_places">Discover Places</string>
    <string name="txt_search_places">Search Places</string>
    <string name="txt_find_a_good_place_to_hike">Find a good place to hike</string>
    <string name="txt_search_mountains">Search mountains</string>
    <string name="txt_login_info">Login Info</string>
    <string name="txt_help">Help</string>
    <string name="txt_legal_information">Legal Information</string>
    <string name="txt_log_out">Log Out</string>
    <string name="txt_profile_picture">Profile Picture</string>
    <string name="txt_welcome">Welcome to %s</string>
    <string name="txt_title_detail">Mountain Detail</string>
    <string-array name="list_location">
        <item>East Java</item>
        <item>East Java</item>
        <item>Central Java</item>
        <item>West Nusa Tenggara</item>
        <item>East Java</item>
        <item>East Nusa Tenggara</item>
        <item>West Java</item>
        <item>West Sumatra</item>
        <item>Papua</item>
        <item>West Java</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="detail_mountains">
        <item>Mount Bromo (from Sanskrit: Brahma, one of the main gods in Hinduism) or in Tenggerese spelled "Brama", is an active volcano in East Java, Indonesia. This mountain has a height of 2,329 meters above sea level and is located in four districts, namely Probolinggo Regency, Pasuruan Regency, Lumajang Regency, and Malang Regency. Mount Bromo is famous as the main tourist attraction in East Java. As a tourist attraction, Bromo becomes interesting because of its status as an active volcano. Mount Bromo is included in the Bromo Tengger Semeru National Park area.\n\nThe body shape of Mount Bromo is linked between valleys and canyons with a caldera or sea of ​​​​sand covering an area of ​​​​about 10 square kilometers. It has a crater with a diameter of ± 800 meters (north-south) and ± 600 meters (east-west). While the danger area is a circle with a radius of 4 km from the center of the Bromo crater.\n\nDuring the 20th and 21st centuries, Mount Bromo has erupted several times, with regular intervals of 30 years. The largest eruption occurred in 1974, while the last eruption occurred in 2016-present.\n\nFor residents around Mount Bromo, the Tengger tribe, Mount Bromo/Mount Brahma is believed to be a sacred mountain. Once a year the Tenggerese people hold a Yadnya Kasada or Kasodo ceremony. This ceremony takes place in a temple which is under the foot of Mount Bromo and continues to the top of Bromo. The ceremony is held at midnight to early morning every full moon around the 14th or 15th of Kasodo (tenth) month according to the Javanese calendar</item>
        <item>Mount Semeru or Mount Meru is a conical volcano in East Java, Indonesia. Mount Semeru is the highest mountain on the island of Java, with a peak of Mahameru, 3,676 meters above sea level (masl). This mountain was formed due to the subduction of the Indo-Australian Plate under the Eurasian Plate. Mount Semeru is also the third highest volcano in Indonesia after Mount Kerinci in Sumatra and Mount Rinjani in West Nusa Tenggara. The crater at the top of Mount Semeru is known as Jonggring Saloko.\n\nMount Semeru is administratively included in the area of ​​two regencies, namely Malang Regency and Lumajang Regency, East Java Province. This mountain is included in the Bromo Tengger Semeru National Park area. Semeru has Dipterocarp Hill forest areas, Upper Dipterocarp forests, Montane forests, and Ericaceous Forests or mountain forests. Semeru\'s geographical position is between 8°06\' South Latitude and 112°55\' East Longitude.\n\nIn 1913 and 1946 Jonggring Saloka Crater had a dome with a height of 3,744.8 m until the end of November 1973. In the south, this dome broke At the top of Mount Semeru (Puncak Mahameru) climbers are advised not to go to Jonggring Saloko crater, also prohibited from climbing from the south side, due to the presence of toxic gases and lava flow. This poisonous gas is known as Wedhus Gembel (Javanese which means "dreadlocks goat", which is a goat that has hair like dreadlocks) by local residents. The temperature at the peak of Mahameru ranges from 4-10 degrees Celsius, at the peak of the dry season minus 0 degrees Celsius, and ice crystals are found. The weather is often foggy, especially in the afternoon, evening and night. The wind blows hard, in December - January there are often storms.\n\nWedus Gembel erupts every 15-30 minutes at the peak of Mount Semeru which is still active. In November 1997, Mount Semeru erupted 2990 times. During the day the wind direction is towards the peak, so avoid coming during the day at the peak, because the toxic gases and eruptions lead to the peak.\n\nThe eruption is in the form of white, gray to black smoke with an eruption height of 300-800 meters. The material that comes out in each eruption is in the form of ash, sand, gravel, and even flaming hot stones which are very dangerous if climbers are too close. In early 1994 hot lava flowed down the southern slopes of Mount Semeru and had claimed several lives, although the view of the hot river winding towards the sea was a very interesting spectacle.\n\nThe eruption in early January 2021 resulted in the population of 5 sub-districts on the slopes. Semeru; Candipuro District, Pasrujambe District, Senduro District, Gucialit District, and Pasirian District. The PVMBG appealed to the public not to carry out activities within a 1 km radius of the summit crater of Mount Semeru and a distance of 4 km to the crater opening in the south-southeast sector, and to be aware of hot clouds falling, lava avalanches, and lava along rivers/valleys flowing through the river. originates at the top of Mount Semeru. The radius and distance of this recommendation will be continuously evaluated to anticipate if there are signs of changes in the threat of danger.\n\nSoe Hok Gie, an Indonesian activist figure and student of the Faculty of Letters at the University of Indonesia, died on Mount Semeru in 1969 due to inhaling toxic fumes on Mount Semeru. . He died along with his colleague, Idhan Dhanvantari Lubis.\n\nIn general, the climate in the Mount Semeru region belongs to climate type B (Schmidt and Ferguson) with 927 mm - 5,498 mm of rain per year with 136 days of rain per year and the rainy season falls. in November - April. The air temperature at the peak of Semeru ranges from 0 - 4 degrees celsius.\n\nThe average temperature ranges from 3 °C - 8 °C at night and early morning, while during the day it ranges from 15 °C - 21 °C. Sometimes in some areas there is a small snowfall when the rainy season changes to the dry season or vice versa. The cold temperatures along this route are not solely caused by still air, but also supported by strong winds that blow into this area causing the air to get colder.\n\nThis mountain is included in the Bromo Tengger Semeru National Park area. This National Park consists of mountains and valleys covering an area of ​​50,273.3 hectares. There are several mountains in the Mt. Tengger Caldera, including; Mt. Bromo (2.392m) Mt. Batok (2,470m) Mt.Kursi (2,581m) Mt.Watangan (2,662m) Mt.Widodaren (2,650m). There are four lakes (ranu): Ranu Pani, Ranu Regulo, Ranu Kumbolo and Ranu Darungan.\n\nFlora in the Mount Semeru area has various types but mostly fir trees, acacia, pine, and Jamuju species. Meanwhile, the undergrowth is dominated by kirinyuh, reeds, tembelekan, harendong and white edelwiss. Edelwis is also commonly found on the slopes leading to the summit of Semeru.There are also several types of endemic orchids that live around the southern part of Mount Semeru.\n\nMany fauna that inhabit Mount Semeru include: panther, budeng, mongoose, deer, deer, etc. Meanwhile, at Ranu Kumbolo there are grouses that still live in the wild.\n\nThe first people to climb this mountain were Clignet and Winny Brigita (1838), a Dutch geologist. They took the route from the southwest via Widodaren. Then Junghuhn (1945), a Dutch botanist, climbed from the north via Mount Ayek-ayek, Mount Inder-inder and Mount Kepolo. In 1911 Van Gogh and Heim passed through the northern slopes and after 1945 generally the ascent was carried out via the northern slopes via Ranu Pani and Ranu Kumbolo as it is today.\n\nAccording to Javanese beliefs written in the ancient book Tantu Pagelaran dating from the 15th century, Long ago, the island of Java was floating in the vast ocean, tossed about and constantly shook. The gods decided to nail the island of Java by moving Mount Meru in India to the island of Java. the tortoise so that the mountain could be transported safely.\n\nThe gods placed the mountain on the first part of the island they came across, namely in the western part of the island of Java. But the weight of the mountain caused the eastern tip of the island to be lifted up. Then they moved it to the eastern part of the island of Java. When Mount Meru is brought to the east, the scattered fragments of Mount Meru create a mountain range on the island of Java that extends from west to east. However, when the peak of Meru was moved to the east, the island of Java was still tilted, so the gods decided to cut off part of the mountain and place it in the northwest. This fragment formed Mount Pawitra, which is now known as Mount Pananggungan, and the main part of Mount Meru, the abode of Lord Shiva, now known as Mount Semeru. When Sang Hyang Shiva came to the island of Java, he saw many Jawawut trees, so the island was called Java.\n\nThe geographical environment of the islands of Java and Bali is indeed compatible with the symbols of Hinduism. In Hinduism there is a belief about Mount Meru, Mount Meru is considered the home of the gods and as a means of connecting between the earth (humans) and Heaven. Many Javanese and Balinese people still regard the mountain as the abode of Gods, Hyangs, and spirits.\n\nAccording to the Balinese, Mount Mahameru is believed to be the father of Mount Agung in Bali and is respected by the Balinese people. The offering ceremony to the gods of Mount Mahameru is performed by the Balinese. After all, the ceremony is only carried out once every 8-12 years only when people receive a magical voice from the god of Mount Mahameru. In addition to the offering ceremony, the Balinese often come to the Widodaren Cave area to get holy Tirta.\n\nThe record of the first recorded eruption is estimated at 1818. In the 1829-1878 range there were also several eruptions until 1913 but not much documented information. Eruptions in the 19th century AD occurred in 1829, 1830, 1832, 1836, 1838, 1842, 1844, 1845, 1848, 1851, 1856, 1857, 1860, 1864, 1867, 1872, 1877, and 1878. it erupted again in 1884 to 1899.\n\nIn 1941-1942, long duration volcanic activity was recorded. The Center for Volcanology and Geological Hazard Mitigation (PVMBG) stated that the lava flow occurred in the period from September 21, 1941 to February 1942. At that time, the eruption reached the eastern slope with a height of 1,400 to 1,775 meters. Volcanic material piled up the Bantengan irrigation post.\n\nSeveral volcanic activities were also recorded in succession in 1945, 1946, 1947, 1950. They erupted again in succession from 1951 to 1961 and 1963. Successive eruptions occurred again from 1967 to 1969. and from 1972 to 1990. The next eruption was followed in 1992 and 1994. The eruption in 1994 was horrific because it claimed the lives of 7 people and people were swept away by the lava.\n\nOn December 1, 1977, lava avalanches produced hot clouds of avalanches with distance up to 10 km in Twins Besuk. The observed volume of volcanic material deposits reached 6.4 million cubic meters. Hot clouds also point to the Besuk Kobokan area. At that time, rice fields, bridges and residents\' houses were damaged. Volcanic activity continued and was recorded in 1978–1989.\n\nPVMBG also recorded volcanic activity of this mountain in 1990, 1992, 1994, 2002, 2004, 2005, 2007 and 2008. In 2008, several eruptions were recorded, namely in the range of 15- May 22, 2008.\n\nOn 12 June 2006, the Tanjung Perak Maritime Meteorology and Geophysics Agency (BMKG) recorded a volcanic earthquake with a magnitude of 1.8 on the Richter Scale (SR) due to the activity of Mount Semeru (3,676 masl).\n\nOn December 4, 2021 at 15.10 WIB, Mount Semeru erupted and emitted hot clouds towards Besuk Kobokan, Sapitarang Village, Pronojiwo District. The lava fall traveled with a sliding distance of 500-800 meters, with the center of the fall 500 meters below the crater. Meanwhile, volcanic earthquakes related to eruptions, avalanches and gusts of crater smoke have occurred as many as 54 earthquake eruptions or eruptions, 4 avalanches earthquakes, and 18 earthquake gusts.</item>
        <item>Mount Prahu (sometimes spelled Gunung Prau) (2,590 masl) is located in the Dieng Plateau area, Central Java, Indonesia. Mount Prahu is located at coordinates 7°11′13″S 109°55′22″E. Mount Prahu is the boundary between four regencies, namely Batang Regency, Kendal Regency, Temanggung Regency and Wonosobo Regency.\n\nThe peak of Mount Prahu is a vast prairie that extends from west to east. We can find small hills and savanna with few trees at the top. Mount Prahu is the highest peak in the Dieng Plateau area, with several lower peaks in the vicinity, including Mount Sipandu, Mount Pangamun-amun, and Mount Juranggrawah.\n\nThis mountain is now one of the main tourist destinations in the Dieng tourist area. as nature tourism.\n\nIn the dense forest on the slopes of Mount Prahu that leads to Kendal and Batang, you can find pitcher plants endemic to Java, namely Nepenthes gymnamphora which grows together with ferns resam (Glichenia linearis). Around the peak, there are Javanese edelweiss flowers (Anaphalis maxima and Anaphalis longifolia). In the forest area of ​​Mount Prahu, you can still find typical Javanese animals such as the Javan leopard (Panthera pardus melas), Javan skunk (Mydaus javanensis) and Javan eagle (Nisaetus bastelsi).\n\nThere are at least six routes that are commonly used to climb Mount Prahu. , namely:\n\n- Dieng, Kalilembu, and Patakbanteng, Kejajar, Wonosobo (southwest/south) lines\n- Igirmranak, Kejajar, Wonosobo (southeast) lines\n- Kenjuran, Sukorejo, Kendal (from the east)\n- The Pranten Line, Bawang, Batang Regency (from the northwest)\n- The Wates Line, Temanggung (from the southeast)\n- The Ngelak Line, Batang (from the north)</item>
        <item>Mount Rinjani is a mountain located on the island of Lombok, West Nusa Tenggara. The mountain which is the second highest volcano in Indonesia with an altitude of 3,726 masl and located at latitudes 8º25\' South Latitude and 116º28\' East Longitude is a favorite mountain for Indonesian climbers because of its beautiful scenery. This mountain is part of the Mount Rinjani National Park which has an area of ​​about 41,330 ha and this will be proposed to increase it to 76,000 ha to the west and east.\n\n Administratively this mountain is located in three districts: East Lombok, Central Lombok, and West Lombok.\n\nMount Rinjani with the highest point of 3,726 m above sea level, dominates most of the scenery of the northern part of Lombok Island.\n\nTo the west of the Rinjani cone there is a caldera with an area of ​​about 3,500 m × 4,800 m, extending east and west. In this caldera, there is Segara Anak (segara = sea, lake) covering an area of ​​​​11,000,000 square meters with a depth of 230 m. The water flowing from this lake forms a very beautiful waterfall, flowing through a steep ravine. In Segara Anak there are many goldfish and tilapia so they are often used for fishing. The southern part of this lake is called Segara Endut.\n\nOn the east side of the caldera there is Mount Baru (or Mount Barujari) which has a crater measuring 170m×200 m with an altitude of 2,296 – 2376 m above sea level. This small mountain last erupted on October 25, 2015 and November 3, 2015, after previously being recorded as erupting in May 2009 and in 2004. If the 2004 eruption did not take any lives, this 2009 eruption has indirectly killed 31 people, due to flooding. a flash on the Kokok (River) Tanggek due to the pressure of lava into Segara Anak. Previously, Mount Barujari was recorded as erupting in 1944 (as well as its formation), 1966, and 1994.\n\nIn addition to Mount Barujari, there is also another crater that has erupted, called Mount Rombongan.\n\n Stratigraphically, Mount Rinjani is covered by sedimentary rock. Neogene clastics (including limestone), and localized by Oligo-Miocene volcanic rocks. The Quaternary volcano itself produces mostly pyroclastic flows, interspersed with lava in some places. The lithology records some of the eruptions known in history. Since 1847 there have been 7 eruptions, with the shortest resting period 1 year and the longest 37 years.\n\nAs with other volcanoes, Koesoemadinata (1979) stated that the activity of Rinjani volcano after the formation of the caldera was rebuilding. Its activities are in the form of effusions that produce lava and explosives that form pyroclastic deposits. Lava is generally black in color, and when it oozes it looks like foam. The eruption after the caldera formation was relatively weak, and the lava released by the cones of Mt. Barujari and Mt. Rombongan was relatively more alkaline than other volcanic lavas in Indonesia. The possibility of hot clouds when the eruption peaked is very small. Eruption materials are generally deposited in the interior of the caldera only.\n\nLava flows, eruptive lava, rain lava, and hot cloud avalanches are likely to lead to Kokok Putih to Batusantek. Hot clouds of avalanches can occur along new lava flows that are still moving, although the probability is small.\n\nThe shape of the Segara Anak Caldera which sways to the west-east is thought to be related to the fracture structure in the bedrock. Rinjani Volcano, which is located in the western part of the Banda Inner Arc system, was formed by the Indian Ocean floor subduction activity under the edge of the Southeast Asian Plate. The subduction path which is located in the south shows the presence of a north-south trending compression force. The bedrock fracture with a west-east trend, which affects the shape of the caldera, is thus interpreted as a release fracture caused by tensile forces. The structure was formed at least since the beginning of the Quaternary Period. Mount Rinjani is the second highest active volcanic mountain in Indonesia. The peak of Mount Rinjani is the destination of most of the adventurers and nature lovers who visit this area because if you have managed to reach the top it is a matter of pride. The enthusiasm of the nature lover community throughout the archipelago and even from abroad in climbing activities is quite large, this is evidenced by the increasing number of visitors who climb every year. Mass climbing activities are carried out from July to August, in August (mid) climbing participants are generally dominated by students from all over Indonesia who want to celebrate the Independence Day of the Republic of Indonesia at the summit of Mount Rinjani and Lake Segara Anak through activities "Tapak Rinjani" which is held regularly every year by a group of nature lovers on the island of Lombok in collaboration with the Mount Rinjani National Park Office.\n\nThe main charm of the very prospective Mount Rinjani National Park is Lake Segara Anak, this location can be reached from two official climbing routes, namely the Senaru hiking trail and the hiking trail Sembalun.\n\nTo visit Segara Anak Lake from the Senaru route, it takes about 7 – 10 hours to walk (± 8 Km) from the gate of the hiking trail. Meanwhile, from the Sembalun hiking trail, it takes 8-10 hours. Lake Segara Anak with a height of ± 2,010 m above sea level and a lake depth of about ± 230 meters has a shape like a crescent moon with an area of ​​about 1,100 Ha.\n\nAround Segara Anak Lake there is a fairly wide and flat land, it can be used for camping/camping, also visitors can fish in the lake or soak in hot water containing sulfur.\n\nOther objects around Segara Anak Lake are the Upper Koko Puteq River, ± 150 meters from Segara Anak Lake. In addition, there are also Goa Susu, Goa Manik, Goa Payung, Goa Susu which is believed to be a medium for self-reflection and is often used as a place to meditate. While at the bottom of Segara Anak Lake there is a hot spring (Aik Kalak Pengkereman Jembangan) which is commonly used to test and bathe magical objects (swords, kris, badik, spears, machetes, etc.) Soaking it indicates that the objects are ugly/does not have supernatural powers, on the other hand, if the objects remain intact, it means that the objects have supernatural powers/are believed to have efficacy.\n\nRinjani has the best panorama among the mountains in Indonesia. Every year (June-August) it is visited by many nature lovers ranging from local residents, students, nature lovers.\n\nThe average air temperature is around 20 °C; as low as 12 °C. Strong winds at the peak usually occur in August.\n\nBesides the peak, a place that is often visited is Segara Anakan, a lake located at an altitude of 2,000m above sea level. To reach this location, we can climb from Senaru village or Sembalun Lawang village (the two closest entry points at an altitude of 600m above sea level and 1150m above sea level) in the Sembalun area which is famous as the Ashitaba plantation area.\n\nThere are four official hiking trails to get to Mt. Rinjani, Sembalun Line (East Lombok), Senaru Line (North Lombok), Aik Berik Trail (Central Lombok), and Timbanuh Line (East Lombok).\n\nMost climbers start the ascent from the Sembalun route and end the climb at Senaru, because they can save 700m altitude. The Sembalun route is rather long but flat, and the weather is hotter because it passes through the scorching savanna (cold temperatures but direct sun radiation burns the skin). sun cream is highly recommended.\n\nFrom the Senaru Route, the climb is uninterrupted, but the weather is gentle as it goes through the forest. From these two locations it takes about 7 hours to walk to the lip of the ridge at an altitude of 2,641m above sea level (arriving at Plawangan Senaru or Plawangan Sembalun). In this place the view towards the lake, as well as to the outside is very good. From Plawangan Senaru (if going up from Senaru direction) down to the lake through a steep wall to an altitude of 2,000 meters above sea level) which can be reached in 2 hours. On the lake we can camp, fishing (Carper, Mujair) a lot. Lombok residents have a tradition of visiting Segara Anak to soak in hot springs and fishing.\n\nTo reach the top (from the lake) you have to walk up a 700m high west wall and climb a 1,000m high ridge which is taken in 2 stages and 3 hours. and 4 hours. The first stage is to Plawangan Sembalun, the last camp to wait for the morning. The summit attack is usually done at 3 am to look for the beautiful moment - the sunrise at the top of Rinjani. The journey to the Peak is quite passable; because climbing on the crater rim with a mediocre margin of safety. Terrain of sand, rock, soil. The last 200 meters of altitude must be traversed with difficulty, because one step forward is followed by half a step down (fallen in gravel). Create a highlander - this is the most challenging and preferred place because the tough terrain pays off with its beautiful natural scenery. Mount Agung in Bali, Mount Raung in Banyuwangi and Mount Tambora in Sumbawa are clearly visible when the weather is good in the morning. To climb Rinjani no tools are needed, just stamina, patience and passion of climbers.\n\nThe whole trip can be achieved in a three-day and two-night program, or if you want to see two other objects: Susu Cave and Mount Baru Jari (a child of Mount Rinjani with a crater). new in the middle of the lake) need an additional two days of travel. Logistics preparation is very necessary. It is recommended to use the services of an experienced local guide to risk getting lost and still respect the local traditional culture.\n\nAt the UNESCO I Global Geopark Council meeting in Torquay, England on August 24, 2016, the UN Agency for Education, Knowledge and Culture UNESCO included the name of Mount Rinjani in the list of requests for status determination as a Global Earth Park or Global Geopark. Mount Rinjani is included in the list of 18 new applications for Global Earth Park status.\n\nIf Mount Rinjani is designated as a Global Geopark by UNESCO, it will become the third Global Earth Park in Indonesia, in addition to the Batur Geopark in Bali and the Gunung Sewu Geopark located in three provinces of Central Java, Yogyakarta, and East Java.\n\nCertainty whether or not Mount Rinjani is accepted as a Global Earth Park/Global Geopark will be submitted in April 2018, and the submission of the Global Geopark charter will be held in Italy in September 2018. The existence of Mount Rinjani is also This is the reason why West Nusa Tenggara Province was appointed as the host of the Asia Pacific Geopark Networks Symposium or a meeting of all Geopark members throughout Asia Pacific in 2019.</item>
        <item>Mount Ijen is a volcano located on the border of Banyuwangi Regency and Bondowoso Regency, East Java, Indonesia. This mountain has a height of 2,386 meters above sea level and is located side by side with Mount Merapi. Mount Ijen last erupted in 1999. One of the most famous natural phenomena of Mount Ijen is the blue fire in the crater located at the top of the mountain. Climbing this mountain can be started from two places, namely from Banyuwangi or from Bondowoso.\n\nTo reach the crater of Mount Ijen in Banyuwangi, visitors can use the economy train to Banyuwangi and get off at Banyuwangi City Station then take a motorcycle taxi to the Licin District and Banyusari Village. From Banyusari, the journey continues to Paltuding by taking a sulfur transport truck or using a bus and getting off at Banyuwangi city then taking an ojek can go directly to Paltuding or to Banyusari Village as well but by using the bus the fare issued will be more expensive. The main gateway to the Ijen Crater Tourism Park Nature Reserve is located in Paltuding, which is also the PHPA (Forest Protection and Nature Conservation) Post. The alternative route is Bondowoso - Wonosari - Tapen - Sempol - Paltuding. Other facilities that can be enjoyed by visitors include tourist huts and stalls selling climbing needs to witness the beauty of Ijen crater. From Paltuding on foot with a distance of about 3 km. The initial trajectory as far as 2 KM is quite heavy because it is uphill. Most of the trails are with a slope of 25-35 degrees. In addition to going uphill, the soil structure is also sandy so that it adds to the weight of the footsteps because they have to hold their weight so they don\'t fall backwards. After resting at Warung Pos Bundar (a unique post because it has a circular shape), the next path goes up a bit steep and slippery, then the last 1 KM is relatively gentle, but tourists / climbers are treated to a very beautiful view of the mountain range. To go down to the crater, you have to traverse a rocky terrain as far as 800 meters with steep conditions up to a slope of 45 degrees.\n\nIjen Crater is an acidic crater lake located at the top of Mount Ijen with a lake depth of 200 meters and a crater area of ​​up to 5,466 Hectares. Ijen crater lake is known to be the largest strong acid lake in the world. Ijen Crater is located in the Ijen Tourism Park Nature Reserve, Bondowoso Regency and Banyuwangi Regency, East Java. The phenomenon of the eternal blue fire is inside the Ijen crater, and this natural sight only occurs in two places in the world, namely Ethiopia (Mount Dallol) and Ijen. Blue fire can only be seen by the human eye when there is no light, therefore the ideal time to see it is 2 to 4 in the morning, because climbing Mount Ijen only starts at 2 in the morning. From Ijen Crater, we can see other mountain views in the Ijen Mountains complex, including the peak of Mount Marapi which is east of Ijen Crater, Mount Raung, Mount Suket, and Mount Rante.\n\nMany events are often held, especially by the Banyuwangi Regency Government which is currently actively promoting Ijen Crater in its list of tourist attractions. These events include: Tour de Ijen (now renamed \'International Tour de Banyuwangi Ijen\'), Jazz Ijen Banyuwangi, and so on.</item>
        <item>Mount Kelimutu is a volcano located on the island of Flores, NTT Province, Indonesia. The location of this mountain is precisely in Pemo Village, Kelimutu District, Ende Regency. The mountain has three lakes. Archived 2017-03-04 at the Wayback Machine. crater at the top. This lake is known as the Three Colors Lake because it has three different colors, namely red, blue, and white. However, these colors always change over time.\n\nKelimutu is a combination of the words "keli" which means mountain and the word "mutu" which means boiling. According to local people\'s beliefs, the colors in Kelimutu lake have their own meaning and have a very powerful natural power.\n\nThe lake or Tiwu Kelimutu is divided into three parts that correspond to the colors in the lake. The blue lake or "Tiwu Nuwa Muri Koo Fai" is a gathering place for the souls of young people who have died. The red lake or "Tiwu Ata Polo" is a gathering place for the souls of people who have died and as long as they live they always do evil / sorcery. While the white lake or "Tiwu Ata Mbupu" is a gathering place for the souls of old people who have died.\n\nThe residents around Lake Kelimutu believe that when the lake changes color, they must give offerings to the spirits of those who have died. has died.\n\nThe area of ​​the three lakes is about 1,051,000 square meters with a water volume of 1,292 million cubic meters. The boundary between the lakes is a narrow rock wall that is prone to landslides. This wall is very steep with a slope angle of 70 degrees. The height of the lake walls ranges from 50 to 150 meters.\n\nInitially this area was discovered by the lio Van Such Telen, a citizen of the Dutch Father Mama Lio, in 1915. Its beauty was widely known after Y. Bouman described it in his writings in 1929. Since then After that, foreign tourists began to come to enjoy the lake which is known to be haunted by the local community. Those who come are not only lovers of beauty, but also researchers who want to know about this very rare natural occurrence as well.\n\nThe Kelimutu area has been designated a National Nature Conservation Area since February 26, 1992.\n\n- Dipterocarp Hill Forest is a forest area which is found at an altitude between 300 - 750 meters.\n- Hill Dipterocarp Forest 300 - 750 meters\n- Upper Dipterocarp Forest at an altitude of 750 - 1,200 meters\n- Montane Forest 1,200 - 1,500 meters\n- Ericaceous Forest > 1,500 meters</item>
        <item tools:ignore="Typos">Mount Patuha is a mountain located in Rancabali, Ciwidey, Bandung Regency, West Java which has a height of 2,434 meters. Mount Patuha has a very exotic crater, namely a white crater. The crater that was formed from the eruption of Mount Patuha has a crater wall and white water.\n\nMount Patuha has an area of ​​Bukit Dipterocarp forest, Upper Dipterocarp forest, Montane forest, and Ericaceous Forest or mountain forest.\n\nOld Man is a nickname that given to Mount Patuha, because he is thought to be very old. The type "B" volcano appeared to the earth\'s surface when the Bandung Plateau was still the ocean floor. At that time, the earth\'s crust was still undergoing revolutionary changes, folding and formation of volcanoes. One of these volcanoes is Mount Patuha. The mountain emerged from the surface of the ocean floor so that later gave birth to a new plain that stretched from the area now called Ciwidey in the west to Pangalengan in the east. Even now if you walk in the middle of tea plantations in the Pangalengan area, you can still find volcanic terraces.\n\nMount Patuha, according to records, has erupted twice. The first eruption occurred in the 10th century and left a crater on the western peak. Because the crater dries up, the community named it Kawah Saat. In Sundanese, when it means dry. Long after that, the mountain fell into a deep sleep entering a long rest. The eruptive activity that occurred in the 13th century, gave birth to a second crater in the form of a very beautiful lake. The water can change color, similar to Kelimutu Lake. Sometimes the color of the water is white, so the crater is called Kawah Putih.\n\nKawah Putih is a crater lake from Mount Patuha with a temperature between 8-22 degrees, there are two craters, namely Kawah Saat which is in the west and Kawah Putih which is below it. at an altitude of 2,194 meters. The beauty of Kawah Putih was first revealed thanks to the efforts of Dr. Franz Wilhelm Junghuhn who was traveling in the South Bandung area in 1837. As the name implies, the soil in this area is white due to the mixing of sulfur elements. In addition to the white soil, the lake water in the Kawah Putih area also has a greenish-white color and can change color according to the sulfur content, temperature, and weather.</item>
        <item><![CDATA[Mount Kerinci (also spelled "Kerintji", and known as Mount Gadang, Kurinci Volcano, Kerinchi, Korinci, or Indrapura Peak) is the highest mountain in Sumatra, the highest volcano in Indonesia, and the highest peak in Indonesia outside of Papua. Mount Kerinci is located right on the border between West Sumatra Province and Jambi Province, in the Bukit Barisan Mountains, near the west coast, and is located about 130 km south of Padang, West Sumatra Province. This mountain is also the boundary between the Minangkabau Ethnic area and the Kerinci Tribe which is surrounded by dense forest of the Kerinci Seblat National Park and is the habitat of the Sumatran tiger and Sumatran rhino.\n\nThe peak of Mount Kerinci is at an altitude of 3,805 masl, in Kerinci Regency, Jambi Province, here visitors can see in the distance a beautiful view of the cities of Jambi, Padang and Bengkulu. Even the vast Indian Ocean can be seen clearly. Mount Kerinci has a crater area of ​​400 x 120 meters and contains green water. To the east is Lake Bento, the highest clear water swamp in Sumatra. Behind it are Mount Seven with an almost untouched crater.\n\nMount Kerinci is a stratovulcano-type volcano that is still active and last erupted in 2009.\n\nMount Kerinci is conical in shape with a width of 13 km (8 miles) and a length of 25 km (16 miles), extending from north to south. At its peak on the northeast side is a 600 meter (1,969 ft) deep crater filled with green water. Until now, the crater measuring 400 x 120 meters is still active. Mount Kerinci last erupted in July 2019. Based on observations from the Mount Kerinci Observation Post, the height of the ash column due to the eruption reached about 800 meters above the peak.\n\nMount Kerinci is included in the part of the Kerinci Seblat National Park (TNKS). TNKS is a conservation area which has an area of ​​1,484,650 hectares and is located in four provinces, most of which are in the Jambi region. TNKS itself is part of the Bukit Barisan Mountains that extends from north to south on the island of Sumatra. TNKS was also designated as a World Heritage site The Tropical Rainforest Heritage Of Sumatra (TRHS) in 2006.\n\nMount Kerinci is an active type A mountain located about 130 kilometers south of Padang City. Eruption Type : Hawaiian Type Mountain Form : Strato Mountain or Cone Eruption Type : Explosive Eruption Mountain Activity : Type A\n\nLowland plants are dominated by several types of mahogany, there are also giant plants Rafflesia Rafflesia Arnoldi and Giant Suweg Amorphophallus Titanum. Spruce trees also grow on Mount Kerinci. With Leuser National Park, the park is blocked by Lake Toba and Ngarai Sianok. So that some animals that are not found in Leuser Park are here, such as the tapir (Tapirus indicus) and cuscus (Tarsius bancanus).\n\nThere are many Sumatran animals such as elephants, Sumatran rhinos, tigers, sun bears, leopards, except humans. orangutan. Various primates such as gibbons, gibbons, long-tailed monkeys, and Presbytis melapophos. There are also 140 species of birds.\n\nMount Kerinci can be reached by land from Jambi City to SungaiFull City via Bangko. You can also fly from Sultan Thaha International Airport to Depati Parbo Airport in Kerinci Regency, Jambi Province. Can also be reached from Padang, Lubuk Linggau, and Bengkulu. By airplane, you can land in Jambi City or Padang City.\n\nThe natural beauty of the panorama with a wealth of flora and fauna can be found from the lowlands to the peak of Mount Kerinci, not only to be enjoyed but very good for conducting research and education. The climb to the top of Mount Kerinci takes two days 2 nights or 2 days 1 night, starting from the Kersik Tuo Ascent Trail, Kerinci Regency, Jambi Province. plantations of Javanese descent, so the local language is Javanese. From Kersik Tuo we head to the TNKS guard post or R10 at an altitude of 1,611 mdpi by walking about 45 minutes across the tea plantations. From R10 we go to Pintu Jungle with an altitude of 1,682 meters above sea level, the distance is about 2 km with a travel time of approximately 1 hour drive. The terrain is in the form of plantations / people\'s fields, the road conditions are good (asphalt) to the forest boundary.\n\nThe Rimba Door is the initial gate for climbing, located within the forest boundary between fields and heterogeneous forest as the entrance. Pintu Jungle is located at an altitude of 1,682 meters above sea level. Here there is a shelter location and also a water location approximately 200 meters to the left. The distance to Bench Panjang is 2 km or 30 minutes away, the track is a bit steep entering a heterogeneous forest area.\n\nAfter that, on the way to Pesanggrahan or Pos 1 with an altitude of 1,735 meters above sea level, there are two shelters that can be used to rest. Pesanggrahan Medan is still gently sloping distance of 2 km with a travel time of about 45 minutes across the forest area. Hikers can rest at Bench Panjang Pos 2 which is located at an altitude of 1,782 meters above sea level, but there is no shelter here. There is a river that sometimes dries up in the dry season.\n\nTo get to Pesanggrahan 2 or Pos 3 which is about 2 km from Bangku Panjang, it takes about 1.5 hours. The path enters a dense and steep forest area with a slope of 45 to 60 degrees.\n\nPos 3 or Pesanggrahan 2 is located at an altitude of 1,982 meters above sea level and there is a cottage that can be used to rest. To get to Shelter 1 the distance that must be taken is about 3 km with a travel time of 2 hours. On this trajectory sometimes encountered steep terrain with a slope of up to 45 degrees but still met with sloping terrain.\n\nThere is an old hut in Shelter 1 which is at an altitude of 2,505 meters above sea level, here climbers can rest & set up a tent. Because setting up a tent is mandatory in Shelter 1 - Shelter 3 (camp area). To get to Shelter 2 from Shelter 1 the distance that must be taken is 2 km with a travel time of about 3 hours. On this track, you can find ferns with slightly open forest conditions. Shelter 2 has an altitude of 3,056 masl\n\nTo get to Shelter 3 from Shelter 2 the distance that must be traveled is about 1.5 km, it takes about 1.5 hours. The condition of the path is in the form of former water flow so that it will turn into a ditch when it rains. Shelter 3 is located at an altitude of 3,291 masl (camp area) when we arrived at Shelter 3 we were already at the Vegetation Boundary between the forest and the typical volcanic rock trail. Towards the top of Mount Kerinci 3,805 masl, we need to pass the Final Post, namely Tugu Yudha. Only then is Indrapura Peak.\n\nAround Mount Kerinci has at least fifteen lakes, the largest being Lake Kerinci, followed by Lake Gunung Tujuh. The 4,200-hectare Lake Kerinci is located at an altitude of 650 meters (2,130 ft), and is the host of the Lake Kerinci Festival. Seven Mountain Lake is a caldera lake formed in an extinct volcano, and surrounded by seven peaks. Lake Gunung Tujuh is the highest lake in Southeast Asia at 1,996 meters (6,549 ft).]]></item>
        <item><![CDATA[Puncak Jaya Wijaya or Carstensz Pyramid is the highest peak that is part of the Sudirman Range Mountains in Papua Province, Indonesia. Puncak Jaya or the Carstensz Pyramid has a height of 4,884 meters above sea level and around it there is a glacier with the same name, namely the Carstensz glacier, the only tropical glacier in Indonesia, which is left and slowly starting to thin out due to global warming.\n\nThis peak is the highest mountain in Indonesia. Indonesia Oceania region. Puncak Jaya is one of the seven highest peaks in the world.\n\nThe plateau around the peak was originally inhabited before European contact, and the peak is known as Nemangkawi in Amungkal. Puncak Jaya was previously named the Carstensz Pyramid after the Dutch explorer Jan Carstenszoon named it when he first saw a glacier on a mountaintop on a clear day in 1623.\n\nThe snow field (glacier) Puncak Jaya was successfully climbed in early 1909 by a Dutch explorer, Hendrikus Albertus Lorentz with six Kenyah people recruited from Apau Kayan in North Kalimantan. Lorentz National Park which also includes the Carstensz Pyramid, was established in 1919 following reports of this expedition.\n\nIn 1936, the Dutch-initiated Carstensz expedition, unable to determine with certainty which of the three peaks was the highest, decided to attempt a hike. each peak. Anton Colijn, Jean Jacques Dozy and Frits Julius Wissel reach the East Carstensz glacier and Ngga Pulu Peak on 5 December. Due to melting glaciers, the height of Ngga Pulu Peak has become 4,862 meters, but it has been estimated that in 1936 (when the glaciers were still covered by a peak of 13 square kilometers), Ngga Pulu was indeed the highest peak with a height of more than 5,000 meters.\n\nAfterwards Peak Jaya was never climbed until 1962, by an expedition led by Austrian mountaineer, Heinrich Harrer, with three other expedition members, Robert Philip Temple, Russell Kippax, and Albertus Huizenga. Philip Temple from New Zealand, previously led expeditions to the area and pioneered access routes to the mountains.\n\nIn 1963, this peak was renamed Soekarno Peak, after which it was later changed to Puncak Jaya. The name Carstensz Pyramid itself is still used among climbers.\n\nWhile Puncak Jaya is still slightly covered in ice, there are several glaciers on the slopes, including Carstensz Glacier, Northwall Firn West Glacier, and Northwall Firn East Glacier, recently reported to have disappeared. \n\nThe glacier at Trikora Peak in the Maoke Mountains disappeared completely between 1939 and 1962. Since the 1970s, evidence from satellite imagery shows the Puncak Jaya glacier has been shrinking rapidly. Meren Glacier melted between 1994 and 2000. An expedition led by paleoclimatologist Lonnie Thompson in 2010 found that the glacier is disappearing at a rate of 7 meters a year and will disappear completely by 2015.\n\nOther names/spellings: \n\n- Nemangkawi\n- Ngga Pulu ("Ngga" means mountain)\n- Mount Carstensz\n- Carstensz Pyramid\n- Carstensz Peak\n- Jayadikesuma Peak\n- Ndugundugu\n- Mount Soekarno.]]></item>
        <item><![CDATA[Mount Gede is a stratovolcano type volcano located on the island of Java, Indonesia. Mount Gede is within the scope of Gede Pangrango National Park, which is one of the five national parks that were first announced in Indonesia in 1980. This mountain is located in two regencies, namely Cianjur and Sukabumi Regencies, with an altitude of 1,000 - 2,958 m. above sea level, and is at latitudes 106°51\' - 107°02\' East Longitude and 64°1\' - 65°1 South Latitude. The average temperature at the top of Mount Gede is 18 °C and at night the peak temperature is around 5 °C, with an average rainfall of 3,600 mm/year. The main gate to this mountain is from Cibodas and Cipanas.\n\nMount Gede is covered by mountain forest, which includes submontane, montana, to subalpine zones around its peak. The mountainous forest in this area is one of the richest in flora types in Indonesia, even in the Malesia region.\n\nThe first eruption of Mount Gede occurred in 1747. This first eruption was very powerful and caused 2 lava flows to move and can be seen from the Lanang crater. . This eruption had such a huge impact.\n\nIt happened again, small eruptions of Mount Gede in 1761, 1780, and 1832. For more than 100 years this mountain was asleep due to the first eruption. He was shocked again by the 2nd (two) violent eruption in 1840 to be precise on November 12 at 3 in the morning. The shaking was so great that it woke up the people who were fast asleep.\n\nAfter that, the Small Eruptions on Mount Gede came back about 24 times. It is quite dangerous for local residents who live close to Mount Gede.\n\nThe last eruption in 1957 was still categorized as a Small Eruption and until now Mount Gede is still sleeping. But stay alert, Because a mountain that has been dormant for a long time. If it is active again, it will be very dangerous.\n\nGunung Gede has a unique and unique natural condition, this makes Gunung Gede one of the natural laboratories that have attracted the interest of researchers for a long time.\n\nIt was recorded in 1819, C.G.C. Reinwardt as the first person to climb Mount Gede, then followed by F.W. Junghuhn (1839-1861), J.E. Teijsmann (1839), A.R. Wallace (1861), S.H. Koorders (1890), M. Treub (1891), W.M. Docters van Leeuwen (1911); and C.G.G.J. van Steenis (1920-1952) has made a collection of plants as the basis for compiling the book The Mountain Flora of Java, which was published in 1972.\n\nGunung Gede also has a diversity of ecosystems consisting of forest formations of submontane, montana, subalpine; as well as lake, swamp, and savanna ecosystems.\n\nGunung Gede is famous for being rich in various types of birds, as many as 251 species out of 450 species found on the island of Java. Some of these species are rare birds, namely the Javanese eagle (Spizaetus bartelsi) and the Javan celepuk (Otus angelinae).\n\nThe Gunung Gede-Pangrango National Park was designated by UNESCO as a Biosphere Reserve in 1977, and as a Sister Park with a National Park\n \nGunung Gede and the Gede Pangrango National Park area are also attractive natural attractions and are visited by many tourists, both domestic and international. .\n\nSome interesting locations/objects to visit:\n\n- Blue Lake. A small lake measuring five hectares (1,575 meters above sea level) is located 1.5 km from the entrance of Cibodas. This lake always looks blue in the sun, because it is covered in blue algae.\n\n- Cibeureum waterfall. The waterfall which has a height of about 50 meters is located about 2.8 km from Cibodas. Around the waterfall, you can see a kind of red moss which is endemic to West Java.\n\n- Hot Water. Located about 5.3 km or 2 hours drive from Cibodas.\n\n- Kandang Batu and Cage Rhinos. For camping activities and observing plants/animals. Located at an altitude of 2,220 m. above sea level with a distance of 7.8 km or 3.5 hours drive from Cibodas.\n\n- The peak and crater of Mount Gede. Panoramic views of sunset/rise, the expanse of the city of Cianjur-Sukabumi-Bogor clearly visible, interesting geological attractions and observations of typical plants around the crater. At this peak there are three craters that are still active in one complex, namely Lanang, Ratu and Wadon craters. Located at an altitude of 2,958 m. above sea level with a distance of 9.7 km or 5 hours drive from Cibodas.\n\n- Suryakencana Square. A 50-hectare plain covered with edelweiss flower beds. Located at an altitude of 2750 m. above sea level with a distance of 11.8 km or 6 hours drive from Cibodas.\n\n- Bunga Edelweiss. A prehistoric flower located at the top of Mount Gede, an altitude of 2,750 m.\n\nHistory and legend which is the belief of the local community, namely the existence of Grandmother Suryakancana. Suryakancana is the son of Dalem Cikundul or Rd. Aria Wira Tanu I, founder of Cianjur and first regent of Cianjur, the result of his marriage to Princess Jin. The community believes that Grandmother Suryakencana, who incidentally is a genie, still lives around Mount Gede, and becomes the ruler of the Jinn nation on the mountain. At certain times, many people, especially adherents of the Sunda Wiwitan Religion enter the caves around Mount Gede for meditation / meditation or religious ceremonies. 2.5 hours (± 100 km) by car, or Bandung-Cipanas-Cibodas with a time of 2 hours (± 89 km), and Bogor-Salabintana with a time of 2 hours (52 km).]]></item>
    </string-array>
</resources>